

# Baikov Alexey

02.01.1987 (35 years)

# Python developer / Backend developer

Level: Junior, Junior+, Middle-Employment: full time, part time,

Work schedule: remote working, full day

Salary expectations: \$1300

### Contacts

- +7 (929) 053-73-35
- https://t.me/alexbaikov
- alex@baikov.dev
- https://github.com/baikov
- Nizhny Novgorod, Russia

## About

More than 10 years of experience in web development and SEO helped me to acquire skills from every point of Full-stack development. I hope that the new stack and deepening in the backend will allow me to participate in the development of larger and more interesting projects. My goals for this year: to become a Middle+ Python developer and improve my level of English to B2.

# Work Experience

#### Learning new stack

I applied all the studied technologies in practice (project allflags.ru)

A short list of practical skills:

- · VPS administration, work with Heroku, AWS, Yandex.Cloud;
- · Configuring Nginx, Traefik, Prometheus, Grafana;
- Working with Docker and Docker Compose, basics of CI/CD;
- · Codestyle (flake8, black), testing (pytest, coverage), documenting (Sphinx);
- · Working with version control and workflows (git, github, git-flow, github-flow);
- · Working with Django, DRF, PostgreSQL, Redis, Celery, Flower.

■ october 2015 - present (6 years 4 months)

PKF Luidor, Nizhny Novgorod (Car factory / special vehicles)

Web developer, SEO specialist

- Developed a service for finding spare parts by VIN (backend: Django/DRF, frontend: Vue.js);
- Development and SEO of the company's websites on 1C-Bitrix;
- · More than 3 years of experience in remote work.

april 2012 — october 2015 (3 years 7 months)

#### Freelance, own projects

Full-stack developer, SEO specialist

- · Website development and SEO (Joomla, WordPress, 1C-Bitrix, OpenCart).
- september 2011 april 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Redox, Moscow (commerce / health products)

**Product Manager** 

Redox, Nizhny Novgorod (retail / health products)

Sales Manager

Telma Soft, Nizhny Novgorod (software development)

Trainee engineer in the software development and testing department

· Internship while studying at the university

## Education

#### LOBACHEVSKY SUNN

Lobachevsky State University of Nizhny Novgorod

a 2004-2009 (5 years), full time, specialist

Faculty of Computational
Mathematics and Cybernetics
Specialty: Applied Mathematics
and Informatics

Qualification: mathematician, system programmer

# Languages

Russian Native
English Intermediate

## Courses

Docker

2021. slurm.io

Build a Backend REST API with Python & Django

2021, Udemi

Algorithms and Data Structures in Python 3

2021, YouTube

# Projects

#### Country flags

bantov, annago

Search parts by VIN

f https://parts.baikov.dev

baikov/autoparts

#### Books

Python Tricks, Dan Bader
Grokking Algorithms, Aditya Bhargava
Practices of the Python Pro, Dane Hillard
Django 3.0. The practice of developing
websites in python, Dronov V. A.